Habib Akbar

habibakbar@live.com | www.linkedin.com/in/habib-akbar-6a6706126 | 604-445-5639

EDUCATION

IBA UNIVERSITY

MBA in Supply Chain Management and Marketing

KIET UNIVERSITY

Bachelors of Engineering in Electronics

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master 1
Six Sigma Yellow Belt
NEBOSH (Health Safety and
Environment)
Project Management Professional
(PMP) in progress
SCRUM Fundamentals Certified

SKILLS

GENERAL

Courteous

Negotiation

Team Player

Presentation skills

Professional Communication

Multilingual (English, Hindi, Urdu)

PROJECT MANAGEMENT

Budgeting

Scheduling

Forecasting

Risk Management

Stakeholder Management

ARIBA Spend Management

SYSTEM ADMINISTRATOR

Python

ERP: SAP

VM Ware

Java Programming

Microsoft Exchange

Microsoft Office Suite

Windows Server 2003, 2008

Operating systems: Windows, Mac

OSX, Linux

ABOUT ME

I enjoy being able to take projects from their inception to completion. My previous experience has taught me how to lead, communicate, manage deadlines and resources in order to implement change in an organization. My experience with IT also enables me to analyze an company's IT infrastructure to find improvements that can be made to increase efficiency or reduce redundancies. I continue to develop my programming skills as a hobby and enjoy staying informed with technological development. These skills enable to look for ways to automate processes and create efficiencies with the work I am involved in.

EXPERIENCE

Area Manager in Amazon:

June 2020 – To present:

- Review the work forecasts and determine your productivity requirements to produce during the day to meet the overall building objectives
- Partner with other Area Managers to balance labor ensuring that you are operating a balanced and efficient shift while meeting all of your goals
- Support all safety programs and OSHA compliance to ensure a safe work environment for all associates
- Proactively identify and lead process improvement initiatives and Lean tools

Assistant Area Manager in Amazon:

September 2018 to May 2020:

- Helping support daily management of department duties, including allocating labor, leading meetings, assigning job duties, and communicating with internal and external suppliers.
- Tracking and reporting of labor hours.
- Assisting the floor as an associate resource, training associates and verifying SOP compliance.
- Ensuring successful area performance, through tracking, reporting and feedback of associate performance.
- Fully understanding workflow and daily production goals.
- Reviewing and updating SOP as required.
- Assisting in keeping work area clean and organized.
- Identifying and addressing safety hazards within the work area.
- Coaching associates to work safely at all times.
- Participating in safety initiatives.
- Referring all job injuries immediately to Area Manager.

Habib Akbar

habibakbar@live.com | www.linkedin.com/in/habib-akbar-6a6706126 | 604-445-5639

UNILEVER PAKISTAN: PROJECT COORDINATOR

September 2015 – August 2018 (Karachi, Pakistan)

- Worked as member of the product development team to successfully design, test, and launch new products or modify existing products
- Determined and tracked costs on Capital Projects (CAPEX) and worked with other stakeholders to ensure that projects stayed within budget
- Created project timelines (using Microsoft Project) to track progress of each project and report major milestones achieved to management
- Provided leadership, mentoring, and direction to different teams working on other projects throughout the organization
- Oversaw the mechanical restructuring of the plant for the implementation of equipment to an automated system to reduce cost.
- Managed different teams to ensure the completion of day to day tasks.
- Analyzed consumer feedback
- Drive Health Safety and Environment performance for continuous improvements within the Projects department.

HABIB BANK LIMITED: SYSTEMS ADMINISTRATOR

August 2013 – August 2015 (Karachi, Pakistan)

- Supported the IT infrastructure of the organization on a day to day basis. This included troubleshooting computer hardware, network and server maintenance as well as providing support for the ERP software
- Followed ITIL based practices for change management, incident management, problem management and configuration management
- Worked on the implementation of new service desk software as well as other major projects
- Developed user documentation and frequently asked questions lists for end user knowledge base
- Responsible for vendor management to procure IT equipment, software and services
- Helped with the successful management, implementation and roll out of a new operating system